<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjamin Joyce's blog</title>
    <description>Posts about the web, business, and other stuff I do in my free time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 12:56:29 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 12:56:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>AI and Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my design role I have a significant amount of exposure to artificial intelligence (AI). This is a new frontier that presents new opportunities for designers but most articles I’ve read don’t talk about real-world experience designing with AI. Here is my attempt to share some of what I&amp;#39;ve learned about designing with AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&amp;#39;s not pretty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My graduate degree is an MBA with a focus in business analytics. Most of my graduate research was spent preparing and massaging data that could be used to build models. Days and days of preparation. The only difference with creating AIs is that it is typically weeks and weeks of understanding a problem, understanding data, preparing data, and then modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work, especially in the early stages, can&amp;#39;t be outsourced or sent to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome&quot;&gt;Amazon Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; or something similar. In data mining,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-industry_standard_process_for_data_mining&quot;&gt;CRISP-DM&lt;/a&gt; is typically followed to work toward desirable and useful results. Good AI projects follow this methodology as well. Traditionally this work is done by data scientists. However, as teams integrate, designers will be deeply involved too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I learned about CRISP-DM and especially the business understanding and data understanding steps I was amazed at how similar it was to design research. Data scientists did all of the same things as me in the early stages: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/research-things/interviewing-humans-fa198f809c40&quot;&gt;talk to stakeholders&lt;/a&gt; (including product sponsors and individuals involved in the process), research what has been done already, research what others outside of the group have approached similar problems, and brainstorm and sketch based on what was learned. All that work allows both data scientists and designers to really dig into what data is available and consider how the data can be used to help solve the problem at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job as a designer on these types of projects will be to help the team progress while staying focused on the user. I&amp;#39;ve been in the position where the team is working on understanding the data and realizing that it may be impossible to solve the problem in the way originally proposed. Depending on your team that might mean a pivot away from the original idea to something else. The product risk comes from when the team finds something the can do with the data that doesn&amp;#39;t quite solve a problem but could be interesting. You will need to ensure that everyone involved understands what the repercussions are of the pivot. Being such a new field there could be research and development benefit to the company without really benefiting any user. This has been the hardest part of my job. I have not found any golden rule for when to fight against something or pursue. It&amp;#39;s more of a &amp;quot;you&amp;#39;ll know it when you see it&amp;quot; type of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work takes effort. If your team believes that AI can be used to solve a problem be prepared to have this initial work to take more effort than you&amp;#39;re used to with more mature tools. There are so many unknowns with AI that you&amp;#39;ll be iterating between business understanding data understanding, and trying to design the solution constantly. Many times you won&amp;#39;t get the results you were hoping for. Sometimes you&amp;#39;ll see magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sometimes it&amp;#39;s magic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing a computer do something you&amp;#39;ve never seen a computer do can be really exciting. Knowing that we don&amp;#39;t fully understand how the computer is making the decisions is confusing and thought provoking. For example, one project I worked on created a detailed classification of an object in a photo (I can talk broadly about what we did, but can’t say exactly what we were classifying). That object typically is seen outdoors. Our training data set included the object in many different outdoor settings. I learned that a customer might take a photo of this object with another person in frame, which wasn’t something we had in our training data. I decided to test the model by adding a person into a validation photo. The model worked well, ignored the person, and correctly classified the object. I tried many different types of people in different validation photos and everything worked fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I tested some dogs. Then I tested some cats. Apparently our model was a dog lover because the classifications were all over the place when a dog was in the photo, but cats didn’t affect the classification confidence or accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a finding that was a little funny, a little spooky, and showed the value a designer can bring to AI projects. I wouldn’t have thought about testing the model with pets or people if I didn’t take the time to do discovery work. We then created data that included different pets and retrain the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Final thought&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Should designers know how to code” was the big question for the last 10 years. I believe the question should now be, “should designers know statistics?” My thoughts on that question are the same as the code question. Good designers know the people, the problem, the business, and the technology which is delivering a solution to a problem. That technology may now include data science and math. I don’t think that an effective designer needs to get their PhD in statistics or data science, but knowing how to work with data will make you much more effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you’d like to talk more about AI, design, or anything else &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenJoyceCT&quot;&gt;@benjoycect&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/2018/01/09/ai-and-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/2018/01/09/ai-and-design.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Illustration: Stormtrooper</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago I illustrated a First Order stormtrooper. It was to practice animating SVG strokes. Check out the animated version on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/zGaNvo&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/stormtrooper.png&quot; alt=&quot;A digital illustration of a stormtrooper&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//illustration/2017/11/07/stormtrooper.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//illustration/2017/11/07/stormtrooper.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Illustration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Featured Work: Madison Tutoring</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago I created a logo for my friend&amp;#39;s business &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.madisontutoring.com/&quot;&gt;Madison Tutoring&lt;/a&gt;. He&amp;#39;s gotten some years out of it so I thought it might be nice to share here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/tutor-color.png&quot; alt=&quot;Madison Tutoring logo&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/illustration/2017/10/30/madison-tutoring.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/illustration/2017/10/30/madison-tutoring.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Featured Work</category>
        
        <category>Illustration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Awkward User Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Anything you get back is helpful&amp;quot; wrote Lyz Nagan in a great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.clockwork.com/news/2017/09/11/770/the_one_thing_you_always_get_from_user_testing&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about the benefits of user testing. I found myself nodding along to all the points made in the article and felt inspired to share an experience of when a user test was extremely awkward but uncommonly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a designer and business analyst on a strategic project at Travelers that was intended to make significant improvements to the customer experience and processes across Operations. The team worked hard to make sure that we were going to improve things and research was a major component of our work. Upon designing a new process that would support the changes, I met with an employee in our back office to validate some of the decisions. This employee had been working at Travelers for over 30 years in a similar function. I presented a prototype that demonstrated the new information flow. I thought that she would poke holes in the flow and some of the slight changes to her role. But before I could even ask a question she dropped a bomb of feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Feedback Bomb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So, you are automating me out of a job?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll never forget the feeling in my stomach when she asked me that. I knew there were going to be changes to her job but I also understood that she was going to take over different but comparable responsibilities. I didn&amp;#39;t know how to respond. The product owner who was with me for the test and I made eyes at each other. This was feedback that I was not prepared for. The product owner and I talked through the changes but I could tell that she was not satisfied with the answer. She explained that she was close to retirement and not excited about or expecting to have to learn a whole new job right before that milestone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on to addressing the flows and she quickly validated the design decisions. Normally positive feedback on these decisions would mean that we could move forward. However, my title is experience designer and I knew that the experience for this key employee would be negative and that would hurt her and our business goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was some of the most important feedback we received for the whole project. It caused us to take a hard look at all the people affected by the process on an individual level. We worked with HR and the training team to create programs that would ease the employees into the changes instead of throwing a new process at them and forcing them to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting this very unexpected feedback changed me as a designer. I believe that I was drawn to this profession because of the empathy that it requires and the personal connections that must be made to gain that empathy. Up until that point in my career I had received &amp;quot;negative&amp;quot; feedback on my designs but never something so personal. What I learned is that because I design experiences that can have radical effects on people&amp;#39;s lives I should be ready for radical feedback. This feedback can be the most uncomfortable but also the most valuable in helping you grow as a designer and a person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/2017/10/30/awkward-user-testing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/2017/10/30/awkward-user-testing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Featured Work: Huckle Buckle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I got some feedback today that made me want to share some of my visual design chops. I came up with a mobile game idea today. The game is called Huckle Buckle. It takes the concept of the &amp;quot;you&amp;#39;re getting warmer&amp;quot; game and brings it to a grand scale. I still have to work out all the details, but basically there is a reward that is in an unknown location to the user. The user walks or runs around using the feedback from the game to get to the location of the reward. As they move the map is updated to show their route. Take a look and let me know what you think &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenJoyceCT&quot;&gt;@BenJoyceCT&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/hucklebuckle.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the Huckle Buckle game that includes hot and cold indicators and a map&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/08/07/huckle-buckle.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/08/07/huckle-buckle.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Featured Work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Illustration: Eggman</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m excited to have Eggman be my first little illustration that I&amp;#39;m sharing. Eggman was a character I made up in grade school and have been playing with ever since. If only I could find the hundreds of MS Paint files with my Egg people comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/Eggman.png&quot; alt=&quot;A digital illustration of Eggman; an egg with super powers&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//illustration/2017/08/06/eggman.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//illustration/2017/08/06/eggman.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Illustration</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Featured Work: Communication Platform</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In August of 2015 it was announced that the CEO of Travelers was stepping down due to illness. The incoming CEO, Alan Schnitzer, was taking over for a beloved leader and wanted to show that he would continue a tradition of honest communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reinvent how employees interact with the CEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was selected to lead the design of the product. We kicked off with a discovery phase that included interviews with Alan, executive leadership, and employees. Since time with the CEO was limited I had to make every interview count. We got straight to the point talking about goals for the product and what he hoped to achieve as CEO. As an added benefit the interviews doubled as reverse mentoring time. I was able to help Alan understand technology capabilities and how user-centered design can improve results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/personas.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of the personas created after discovery&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result of discovery was an understanding of what Alan was hoping to achieve and employee expectations for communication. I used this information to scope the product and determine goals. Additionally, the discovery phase helped show risk-adverse stakeholders the risk of not allowing employees to have an open communication channel back to Alan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/axure.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes of the project&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/usertest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A user testing the prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I explored solutions to solve the problem. This exploration took the form of creating example content for wireframes and mockups. I got the solutions in front of users and iterated for a week while my development team got the environment set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the focused was narrowed through discovery and framing, the team was able to build and release our first iteration of the product in three weeks. This speed and focus allowed us to release the product to a small group, get feedback, and iterate quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Result&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product met the goals found during discovery. Employees have noted that they have more access to the CEO than they expected. Alan uses the product on a daily basis to share what he thinks is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My efforts on the product were rewarded by Alan. He presented me with the CEO award at the 2016 Annual Shareholders Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Learn more&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn more about the team dynamic, workshops I ran with stakeholders and users, how the IA was determined, or how my mindset around interactive product management changed after this project? Please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:me@benjaminjoyce.com?Subject=Hello&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/08/05/fw-communication-platform.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/08/05/fw-communication-platform.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Featured Work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Featured Work: Self-Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of many featured work articles I&amp;#39;ll post. This one is about a self-service feature I led the design on for Travelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce friction in the post-sales process for personal insurance customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project began with an idea for a solution that centered around a recently published paper on artificial intelligence. While the concept was exciting, it lacked focus about who would benefit from the solution and why. I worked with the team the team to take a step back from the technical implementation of the solution and understand the problem we were trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try a week-long design sprint. The sprint followed the plan and concepts outlined in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesprintbook.com/&quot;&gt;The Sprint Book&lt;/a&gt;. The outcomes from the sprint week were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The product had a concrete goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Underwriters and claims professionals were talked to which gave the team a better understanding of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Concepts created addressed an actual problem rather than blindly attempted to use a technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The new artificial intelligence breakthrough was still part of the &amp;quot;winning&amp;quot; concept, but the proposed use was different than the original concept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A prototype was created that validated what we learned with potential users of the app and business owners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/benjaminjoyce-images/sprint-room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the design sprint room at the end of the week&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sprint week ended the product manager and I looked at everything we learned and started to plan the first iteration. Since this product manager was new to the role and working in agile environments I provided training on the goals of story writing and how to write a good story. I shared everything I had learned from past work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotallabs.com&quot;&gt;Pivotal Labs&lt;/a&gt; and my experience on other agile products. We took some of the persona work and story mapping we had done in the design sprint to write stories that were focused on delivering small pieces of value to the users who fit in the personas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/07/31/fw-self-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/07/31/fw-self-service.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Featured Work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UX Job Interview Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been conducting interviews for various roles in IT and design for about six years. In that time I&amp;#39;ve seen all sorts of interviews, good and bad. These are tips that from my perspective will help a hiring manager really understand you and whether you will be a fit for their team and whether their team is a fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;STAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m interviewing someone I want to know about them first and foremost. In order to get that I want to hear about their role on past experiences. I&amp;#39;ve come across a framework called STAR: &lt;b&gt;S&lt;/b&gt;ituation, &lt;b&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;ask, &lt;b&gt;A&lt;/b&gt;ction, &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt;esult. When someone interviewing you asks you a question that starts with &amp;quot;tell me about a time,&amp;quot; consider the STAR framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a simple example to outline a response that I believe effectively demonstrates the STAR framework. Let&amp;#39;s pretend the interviewer asked, &amp;quot;tell me about a time when you had to work with a team.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, start with the situation, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I was assigned to a project where we had to figure out how to increase the number of donations people who visited the non-profit's website made. It was an agile team that featured me as the designer, two developers, and two people who knew the business of the non-profit well.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really the setup for the rest of your story. It helps the interviewer understand the context of what you&amp;#39;re about to tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, move on to your task. Even if the team accomplished great things together, the interviewer is most interested in hearing about how you specifically worked and contributed to that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example task might be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My role was to understand the users of the site, including their motivations and ability to donate to the non-profit. This research was expected to be turned into an experience design that included both the website and the offline experience which encouraged and made it easier for the people who wanted to donate to do so. It was up to me to help guide the team towards the best approach to the research and make sure that they understood everything so that we built the right solution for the right person.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the interviewer will have a good understanding of the context of your response and know about your past roles beyond the title you put on your resume. You&amp;#39;re now ready to get into the body of your response, the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action part of your response might sound like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I started by having the team go through exercises that helped us understand the problem more. Since the two business members of the team felt like they had a good idea of the problem it was a little hard to convince them that these activities would be valuable. However, after we went through them and they saw that they had gaps in their understanding they were totally onboard. It also helped myself and the developers learn where we had to focus. Next, I created interview questions that we could ask to users who fit the personas we developed during the initial exercises. One of the business members of the team facilitated the interviews with users we recruited through an online service who had visited the non-profit's site but did not donate. We were able to understand their motivations and develop a user journey map. The whole team went through what we had learned and developed a list of opportunities. I created wireframes for the parts that involved a UI and got those in front of more users with a quick and dirty task-based usability study. I made some adjustments then I worked with the business team to create user stories that accurately matched what we had learned were customers expectations. Those stories were executed on by the developers on the team who made further recommendations that were well informed and helped make the new donation experience even better.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action part of the answer would be a great time to show your work if possible. Provide artifacts that were produced as part of the process or point to how your actions influenced a live part of the design. Showing work is much more difficult under a non-disclosure agreement. I prefer when candidates can show me their work but totally sympathize when they can&amp;#39;t. If they describe their work with enough detail then I can usually get a sense of whether their approach would work well with my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you&amp;#39;re at the point where you should describe the results of your effort. Not all stories are tied to a financial result at the time, but should be tied to something that is measurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the result part of your response might sound like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;First, my effort to get the team involved with researching and understanding the people who are interested in the non-profit made it much easier for us to make decisions and support those decisions together when working with the non-profit board. We quickly went from forming to performing because we all worked toward a common, well understood goal. Also, the non-profit is seeing strong returns from my design. Donations are up 20 percent through the website and surprisingly 15 percent through non-web means. The non-profit is now able to provide more services and the board told our team that we would be leading more national-level efforts due to the success of our work with the donations.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not bragging when describing what you did or the results. Don&amp;#39;t try to minimize your efforts. Also, keep everything concise and on-point. Though the example above may read long, it is about two minutes in length at a comfortable speed. If you take the interviewer through this framework when they ask behavioral-based questions then you&amp;#39;ll get to present your best self and have them really understand what you&amp;#39;re about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don&amp;#39;t judge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This suggestion should be obvious to most good candidates (and people), but don&amp;#39;t judge your interviewer by their race, gender, age, way of talking, face, or really anything except the questions they are asking and responses they give you to your questions. I&amp;#39;m young in appearance and have had good conversations with candidates then found out from other interviewers that they commented on my age and asked how I got into my position. Designers are working to understand and create things that help people. You will not get the job if there you have any hint of discrimination. You should also really take a look inward and work toward understanding people better. Your life will be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be real&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no reason not to be yourself in an interview. If you present a version of yourself that isn&amp;#39;t true to who you are then you&amp;#39;re just hurting yourself and the business you&amp;#39;re interviewing with. This stage of the employee experience is all about finding the best company for you. If you don&amp;#39;t present a true version of yourself then you&amp;#39;re putting yourself and the company you&amp;#39;re interviewing with at a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get good sleep the night before, prepare, and bring your best self. Just make sure it is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ask questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve hinted at this through the other tips, but interviews are as much about the company learning if you&amp;#39;re a good fit for them as you finding out if the company is a good fit for you. Ask questions that you&amp;#39;re curious about. Sometimes companies will shield you from their actual culture. If you sense that they are hiding something, ask questions that might be a little uncomfortable for them to answer. Just like you have to be your real self, encourage the interviewer to be their real self.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/30/ux-job-interview-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/30/ux-job-interview-tips.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Decisions Quote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;89% of decisions you make as a designer have nothing to do with type, colors, or grids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//quote/2017/07/30/decisions-quote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//quote/2017/07/30/decisions-quote.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Quote</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
