<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjamin Joyce's blog</title>
    <description>Posts about the web, business, and other stuff I do in my free time.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 11:54:33 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 11:54:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Featured work: Self-Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of many featured work articles I&amp;#39;ll post. This one is about a self-service feature I lead the design on for Travelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduce friction in the post-sales process for personal insurance customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The details of the product itself cannot be discussed as it has not been shared publicly, but I want to share my role. This project began with an idea for a solution that centered around a recently published paper on artificial intelligence. While the concept was exciting, it lacked focus about who would benefit from the solution and why. I worked with the team the team to take a step back from the technical implementation of the solution and understand the problem we were trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try a week-long design sprint. The sprint followed the plan and concepts outlined in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesprintbook.com/&quot;&gt;The Sprint Book&lt;/a&gt;. The outcomes from the sprint week were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The product had a concrete goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Underwriters and claims professionals were talked to which gave the team a better understanding of the problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Concepts created addressed an actual problem rather than blindly attempted to use a technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The new artificial intelligence breakthrough was still part of the &amp;quot;winning&amp;quot; concept, but the proposed use was different than the original concept&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A prototype was created that validated what we learned with potential users of the app and business owners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/benjaminjoyce-images/sprint-room.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of the design sprint room at the end of the week&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sprint week ended the product manager and I looked at everything we learned and started to plan the first iteration. Since this product manager was new to the role and working in agile environments I provided training on the goals of story writing and how to write a good story. I shared everything I had learned from past work with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pivotallabs.com&quot;&gt;Pivotal Labs&lt;/a&gt; and my experience on other agile products. We took some of the persona work and story mapping we had done in the design sprint to write stories that were focused on delivering small pieces of value to the users who fit in the personas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/07/31/fw-self-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//featured%20work/2017/07/31/fw-self-service.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Featured Work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UX Job Interview Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been conducting interviews for various roles in IT and design for about six years. In that time I&amp;#39;ve seen all sorts of interviews, good and bad. These are tips that from my perspective will help a hiring manager really understand you and whether you will be a fit for their team and whether their team is a fit for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;STAR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;#39;m interviewing someone I want to know about them first and foremost. In order to get that I want to hear about their role on past experiences. I&amp;#39;ve come across a framework called STAR: &lt;b&gt;S&lt;/b&gt;ituation, &lt;b&gt;T&lt;/b&gt;ask, &lt;b&gt;A&lt;/b&gt;ction, &lt;b&gt;R&lt;/b&gt;esult. When someone interviewing you asks you a question that starts with &amp;quot;tell me about a time,&amp;quot; consider the STAR framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s a simple example to outline a response that I believe effectively demonstrates the STAR framework. Let&amp;#39;s pretend the interviewer asked, &amp;quot;tell me about a time when you had to work with a team.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, start with the situation, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I was assigned to a project where we had to figure out how to increase the number of donations people who visited the non-profit's website made. It was an agile team that featured me as the designer, two developers, and two people who knew the business of the non-profit well.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is really the setup for the rest of your story. It helps the interviewer understand the context of what you&amp;#39;re about to tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, move on to your task. Even if the team accomplished great things together, the interviewer is most interested in hearing about how you specifically worked and contributed to that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example task might be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;My role was to understand the users of the site, including their motivations and ability to donate to the non-profit. This research was expected to be turned into an experience design that included both the website and the offline experience which encouraged and made it easier for the people who wanted to donate to do so. It was up to me to help guide the team towards the best approach to the research and make sure that they understood everything so that we built the right solution for the right person.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the interviewer will have a good understanding of the context of your response and know about your past roles beyond the title you put on your resume. You&amp;#39;re now ready to get into the body of your response, the action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action part of your response might sound like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I started by having the team go through exercises that helped us understand the problem more. Since the two business members of the team felt like they had a good idea of the problem it was a little hard to convince them that these activities would be valuable. However, after we went through them and they saw that they had gaps in their understanding they were totally onboard. It also helped myself and the developers learn where we had to focus. Next, I created interview questions that we could ask to users who fit the personas we developed during the initial exercises. One of the business members of the team facilitated the interviews with users we recruited through an online service who had visited the non-profit's site but did not donate. We were able to understand their motivations and develop a user journey map. The whole team went through what we had learned and developed a list of opportunities. I created wireframes for the parts that involved a UI and got those in front of more users with a quick and dirty task-based usability study. I made some adjustments then I worked with the business team to create user stories that accurately matched what we had learned were customers expectations. Those stories were executed on by the developers on the team who made further recommendations that were well informed and helped make the new donation experience even better.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The action part of the answer would be a great time to show your work if possible. Provide artifacts that were produced as part of the process or point to how your actions influenced a live part of the design. Showing work is much more difficult under a non-disclosure agreement. I prefer when candidates can show me their work but totally sympathize when they can&amp;#39;t. If they describe their work with enough detail then I can usually get a sense of whether their approach would work well with my team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you&amp;#39;re at the point where you should describe the results of your effort. Not all stories are tied to a financial result at the time, but should be tied to something that is measurable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the result part of your response might sound like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;First, my effort to get the team involved with researching and understanding the people who are interested in the non-profit made it much easier for us to make decisions and support those decisions together when working with the non-profit board. We quickly went from forming to performing because we all worked toward a common, well understood goal. Also, the non-profit is seeing strong returns from my design. Donations are up 20 percent through the website and surprisingly 15 percent through non-web means. The non-profit is now able to provide more services and the board told our team that we would be leading more national-level efforts due to the success of our work with the donations.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not bragging when describing what you did or the results. Don&amp;#39;t try to minimize your efforts. Also, keep everything concise and on-point. Though the example above may read long, it is about two minutes in length at a comfortable speed. If you take the interviewer through this framework when they ask behavioral-based questions then you&amp;#39;ll get to present your best self and have them really understand what you&amp;#39;re about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don&amp;#39;t judge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This suggestion should be obvious to most good candidates (and people), but don&amp;#39;t judge your interviewer by their race, gender, age, way of talking, face, or really anything except the questions they are asking and responses they give you to your questions. I&amp;#39;m young in appearance and have had good conversations with candidates then found out from other interviewers that they commented on my age and asked how I got into my position. Designers are working to understand and create things that help people. You will not get the job if there you have any hint of discrimination. You should also really take a look inward and work toward understanding people better. Your life will be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be real&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no reason not to be yourself in an interview. If you present a version of yourself that isn&amp;#39;t true to who you are then you&amp;#39;re just hurting yourself and the business you&amp;#39;re interviewing with. This stage of the employee experience is all about finding the best company for you. If you don&amp;#39;t present a true version of yourself then you&amp;#39;re putting yourself and the company you&amp;#39;re interviewing with at a disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get good sleep the night before, prepare, and bring your best self. Just make sure it is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ask questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve hinted at this through the other tips, but interviews are as much about the company learning if you&amp;#39;re a good fit for them as you finding out if the company is a good fit for you. Ask questions that you&amp;#39;re curious about. Sometimes companies will shield you from their actual culture. If you sense that they are hiding something, ask questions that might be a little uncomfortable for them to answer. Just like you have to be your real self, encourage the interviewer to be their real self.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/30/ux-job-interview-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/30/ux-job-interview-tips.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Decisions Quote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;89% of decisions you make as a designer have nothing to do with type, colors, or grids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//quote/2017/07/30/decisions-quote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//quote/2017/07/30/decisions-quote.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Quote</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting Slow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After two years of being absent on this blog I&amp;#39;m back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://austinkleon.com/show-your-work/&quot;&gt;show my work&lt;/a&gt;. Like many others I&amp;#39;ve decided to start a side project. It&amp;#39;s called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finlo.io&quot;&gt;Finlo&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is that Finlo will be a better way to stumble upon local places that care deeply about their craft. As of July 2, 2017 it hasn&amp;#39;t launched. This post is about why and how it&amp;#39;s frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the domain for Finlo on April 13, 2017. I thought my first iteration of Finlo would be out by the end of the weekend (a landing page). I&amp;#39;ve worked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://pivotal.io/labs&quot;&gt;Pivotal Labs&lt;/a&gt; in my day job, read &lt;a href=&quot;http://theleanstartup.com/&quot;&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt; (among many other books and articles about lean product development), and have been a vocal proponent of agile product development with everyone I&amp;#39;ve worked with. I also have practiced user experience design and development for 8 years and recently got my MBA. I thought I had all the tools to get something up quickly that I could use to determine whether there is a market for my product and begin discovery exercises to better understand my potential customers. However, I quickly became overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Idea Overload&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick Google search for &amp;quot;idea overload&amp;quot; showed me that I am not the first one to think of the term. The term came to mind when I started thinking about what was different about this side project versus my day job. In my day job, one of the primary components of my work is to help my teams have a specific focus on problems. We work to understand the problem from the user/customer perspective, understand how the problem fits into the larger experience, and frame solutions that can solve the problem. The whole process is really about pulling great ideas out from the clutter. It&amp;#39;s a challenge to successfully accomplish this task with multiple people but I am finding that it is even harder when I am only working with myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reflect on why I am struggling with it I realize that it is because I have no constraints. Right now there are no expectations from anyone else and I&amp;#39;m already making a living. What that leaves me with is too much time to think when what I should be doing is learning. I&amp;#39;ve been so worried about what my first release will look like since Finlo is founded on the principle that people want to seek out well-done and handmade experiences. I want people&amp;#39;s first impression of Finlo (and my first entrepreneurial endeavor) to be incredible. I want people to know that I don&amp;#39;t just care about making money, but am going to work tirelessly to connect people with other people who are making something great. So even though I know I&amp;#39;m just going to be making an informational landing page, I&amp;#39;ve been delaying a release because I don&amp;#39;t think that some descriptive copy is good enough or I learn about a new way that some other company launched and I consider scrapping my approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to be listening to everything I&amp;#39;ve learned in my professional career and focus on learning. So, how am I going to battle idea overload. First, I&amp;#39;m going to stick to the version of &amp;quot;Welcome to Finlo&amp;quot; that I have today, June 18th. It might not be perfect but I will be able to learn from it. Next, I&amp;#39;m going to set a deadline for myself. A tweet from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lin_Manuel?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Ftwitter.com%2Flin_manuel%2Fstatus%2F832175919649456128&quot;&gt;@Lin_Manuel&lt;/a&gt; inspired me to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Deadlines.&lt;br&gt;You know how if you set an alarm for a certain time your brain will wake up just before?&lt;br&gt;Deadlines teach your brain the same way. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/IRImJTmEQ5&quot;&gt;https://t.co/IRImJTmEQ5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Lin-Manuel Miranda (@Lin_Manuel) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Lin_Manuel/status/832175919649456128&quot;&gt;February 16, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a family vacation coming up and my family will always take priority, so I&amp;#39;m going to set myself a doable deadline of July 10th, 2017 to get the landing page up. Be sure to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finlo.io&quot;&gt;Finlo&lt;/a&gt; then to see the first preview of Finlo up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s gotten pretty late and I&amp;#39;m writing a bit more than I expected, but I think it&amp;#39;s important for me to get it out. So in the spirit of release and learn, I&amp;#39;m going to publish this post as a part one. Part two will feature: Websites Seem Harder Now and Get Out of Here, Imposter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodnight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/02/starting-slow.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/business/2017/07/02/starting-slow.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Business</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pace Calculator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I created a small pace calculator for my own use. There are many TODOs, but let me know if something can be done better. I&amp;#39;ll be open sourcing the project later this week. You can take a look at the first iteration of the solution here. Your &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenJoyceCT&quot;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt; is always welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constraints I put on myself were to use vanilla JavaScript, less than 3KB, and as few &amp;quot;wrapper divs&amp;quot; as I could get away with. I will be writing another post when the calculator is on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/css/build/calculator.css&quot;&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;/js/paceCalculator.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;pace-calculator&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;input-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;form class=&quot;pace-calculator__form&quot;&gt;
      &lt;section class=&quot;time pace-calculator__section&quot;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;hour&quot;&gt;HOURS&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;hour&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;colon&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;minute&quot;&gt;MINUTES&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;minute&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;colon&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;second&quot;&gt;SECONDS&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;second&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
      &lt;/section&gt;
      &lt;section class=&quot;distance pace-calculator__section&quot;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;distance&quot;&gt;Distance&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;distance&quot; placeholder=&quot;00.00&quot; required /&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Mile(s)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/section&gt;
    &lt;/form&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;output&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;output__label&quot;&gt;Pace&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;output__value&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;output__pace output__pace--no-value&quot; id=&quot;pace&quot;&gt;00:00:00&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Per Mile&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;button id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Calculate Pace&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;HTML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&quot;pace-calculator&quot;&gt;
  &amp;lt;div class=&quot;input-container&quot;&gt;
    &amp;lt;form class=&quot;pace-calculator__form&quot;&gt;
      &amp;lt;section class=&quot;time pace-calculator__section&quot;&gt;
        &amp;lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;hour&quot;&gt;HH&amp;lt;/label&gt;
        &amp;lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;hour&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
        &amp;lt;span class=&quot;colon&quot;&gt;:&amp;lt;/span&gt;
        &amp;lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;minute&quot;&gt;MM&amp;lt;/label&gt;
        &amp;lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;minute&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
        &amp;lt;span class=&quot;colon&quot;&gt;:&amp;lt;/span&gt;
        &amp;lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;second&quot;&gt;SS&amp;lt;/label&gt;
        &amp;lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;second&quot; placeholder=&quot;00&quot; required /&gt;
      &amp;lt;/section&gt;
      &amp;lt;section class=&quot;distance pace-calculator__section&quot;&gt;
        &amp;lt;label class=&quot;pace-calculator__label&quot; for=&quot;distance&quot;&gt;Distance&amp;lt;/label&gt;
        &amp;lt;input class=&quot;pace-calculator__input&quot; type=&quot;number&quot; id=&quot;distance&quot; placeholder=&quot;00.00&quot; required /&gt;
        &amp;lt;p&gt;Mile(s)&amp;lt;/p&gt;
      &amp;lt;/section&gt;
    &amp;lt;/form&gt;
    &amp;lt;div class=&quot;output&quot;&gt;
      &amp;lt;p class=&quot;output__label&quot;&gt;Pace&amp;lt;/p&gt;
      &amp;lt;div class=&quot;output__value&quot;&gt;
        &amp;lt;p class=&quot;output__pace output__pace--no-value&quot; id=&quot;pace&quot;&gt;00:00:00&amp;lt;/p&gt;
        &amp;lt;p&gt;Per Mile&amp;lt;/p&gt;
      &amp;lt;/div&gt;
    &amp;lt;/div&gt;
  &amp;lt;/div&gt;
  &amp;lt;button id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Calculate Pace&amp;lt;/button&gt;
&amp;lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;JavaScript&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', function() {
  var pace = document.getElementById('pace'); // Get the pace input
  var processResult = document.getElementById('process'); // The main button
  var hours = document.getElementById('hour'); // Get the hour input
  var minutes = document.getElementById('minute'); // Get the minute input
  var seconds = document.getElementById('second'); // Get the second input
  var distance = document.getElementById('distance'); // Get the distance input

  // Watch for the process button to be clicked then run the function
  if(processResult) {
    processResult.addEventListener(&quot;click&quot;, calculatePace, false);
  }

  // The function that calculates pace
  function calculatePace(){
    var paceOutput = 0; // The variable that holds the pace output

    var hoursInSecs = Number(hours.value * 3600); // Takes the value of the hours input, multiplies it by 3600 to hours in seconds, changes the string to a number.

    var minsInSecs = Number(minutes.value * 60); // Takes the minutes input and converts it to a number.

    var secsInSecs = Number(seconds.value); // Takes the seconds input, changes the string to a number.
    var finalDistance = Number(distance.value); // Holds the distance input



    paceOutput = (hoursInSecs + minsInSecs + secsInSecs) / finalDistance; // Calculation for pace and update the paceOutput variable with that value.

    // The function that takes the output of the pace and turns it into a time format for display.
    function getPace(){
      var paceHours = paceOutput / 3600;

      var paceMins = paceOutput / 60; // Separate the total minutes from the total seconds.

      var paceSecs = (paceMins % 1); // Get the remainder of the pace value and multiply it by 60 to convert to seconds

      if(isNaN(paceHours) || isNaN(paceMins) || isNaN(paceSecs)) {
        pace.textContent = &quot;Please enter a number 0-99&quot;;
      } else {
        var finalHours = Math.floor(paceHours);
        var finalMins = Math.floor(paceMins);
        var finalSecs = (paceSecs.toFixed(2) * 100);

        if(finalHours &gt; 0) {
        pace.textContent = String('00'+finalHours).slice(-2) + &quot;:&quot; + String('00'+finalMins).slice(-2) + &quot;:&quot; + String('00'+finalSecs).slice(-2); // Update the pace output placeholder with the minutes and the seconds, only show the value to the closest second.
        } else {
          pace.textContent = String('00'+finalMins).slice(-2) + &quot;:&quot; + String('00'+finalSecs).slice(-2);
        }

        changeClass();
      }
    }

    function changeClass(){
      pace.classList.remove('output__pace--no-value');
    }
    getPace();
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/front-end%20development/2015/08/16/pace-calculator.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/front-end%20development/2015/08/16/pace-calculator.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Image</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just set up an account on AWS and will be using &lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/&quot;&gt;CloudFront&lt;/a&gt; CDN for images. I&amp;#39;ll write about getting CloudFront set up and some of the things I am trying out with &lt;code&gt;srcset&lt;/code&gt; very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/EarthRise.jpg&quot;
     srcset=&quot;http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/EarthRise.jpg 1024w, http://images.benjaminjoyce.com/EarthRise.jpg 640w, http://d3p41d0ahmxvrr.cloudfront.net/Mom-400.jpg 320w&quot;
     sizes=&quot;(min-width: 36em) 33.3vw, 100vw&quot;
     alt=&quot;Earth Rise as Seen From Lunar Surface from NASA on The Commons&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/8GrsJ6&quot;&gt;Earth Rise as Seen From Lunar Surface&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/nasacommons/&quot;&gt;NASA on The Commons&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Altered for speed performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/2015/08/16/first-image.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/2015/08/16/first-image.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My CSS Mistakes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a long time CSS was really confusing to me. I was shocked after every line of code I wrote. Text flowed outside its container, things didn&amp;#39;t position themselves like I expected, and elements I expected to be center sat on the left side of the page. These problems left my CSS with &lt;code&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; declarations and hacks to make things look right. This is my post that would have taught past me how to fix those mistakes and where to get more information. Maybe you have the same problems and this post will help you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Height&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day a friend asked me why part of the text in one of his text inputs was hidden. He accidently set a height on his &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; elements. This isn&amp;#39;t a problem unique to first-time front-end developers. It feels good to set a height on elements. However, setting an explicit height can cause trouble later if you&amp;#39;re not careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;#39;s take a look at my friend&amp;#39;s example with the &lt;code&gt;input&lt;/code&gt; (note that you won&amp;#39;t notice anything wrong in Chrome or desktop Safari, but keep reading).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;select style=&quot;font-size:20px; height: 18px; margin-left: 40%; width: 20%;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;option&gt;Apples&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option&gt;Oranges&lt;/option&gt;
  &lt;option&gt;Bananas&lt;/option&gt;
&lt;/select&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand what is happening we need to get into the box model. If you&amp;#39;ve never heard of the box model, stop and read &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/the-css-box-model/&quot;&gt;The CSS Box Model&lt;/a&gt; on CSS-Tricks. When content is driving the size of the box, padding, border, and margin are calculated based on the edges of the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;986e518c542049dca4bdcf80c5b6a73e&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/986e518c542049dca4bdcf80c5b6a73e/'&gt;Normal Box&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting an explicit height ignores the content and will make the box the size set in the CSS. I didn&amp;#39;t change the padding, border, or margin from the previous example. I did add a height. You can see that the content is now overflowing from the box (that is because the &lt;a href=&quot;https://bocoup.com/weblog/new-overflow-default/&quot;&gt;default&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;code&gt;overflow: visible&lt;/code&gt;). Additionally, the bottom border and the bottom margin are being calculated based on the new position of the bottom of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;216&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;cd4f283aaff1e8ec3515ef2f84608b6e&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/cd4f283aaff1e8ec3515ef2f84608b6e/'&gt;Height Box&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;#39;s say you know you need something to be a certain height. There are a few options. First, you can use the &lt;code&gt;overflow&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/overflow&quot;&gt;property&lt;/a&gt;. Setting &lt;code&gt;overflow-y&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;scroll&lt;/code&gt; might be a tempting solution in our example above. This solution should be avoided in most situations. Imagine scrolling down a webpage only to be stuck in a content box that has its own scroll. An &lt;a href=&quot;http://ux.stackexchange.com/questions/58499/in-page-scrollbars-yes-or-no-or-maybe/#answer-58551&quot;&gt;answer&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://ux.stackexchange.com/users/21165/alexeypegov&quot;&gt;alexeypegov&lt;/a&gt; on UX StackExchange has some good examples of when it might be okay to use &lt;code&gt;overflow-y: scroll&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    You may use nested scrolling panes if they're shown temporary (like in Facebook example you've mentioned in your question: the scrolling list in popup which is shown for a moment and will not break the page scrolling itself).
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    Editable areas like comments may be scrolled while being edited (and reverted back to non-scrollable mode then editing is done).
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
    Web apps which may occupy the whole browser window and avoid scrolling of the content by using dynamic layout so it's OK to use nested scrolling panes (since main content area could never be scrolled anyway).
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides overflow, &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Flexible_boxes&quot;&gt;flexbox&lt;/a&gt; solves many challenges developers have with height. For example, equal height columns can be done with only &lt;a href=&quot;http://clearleft.com/thinks/270&quot;&gt;one line of code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;949835e2077b5e45aab26aadc2967c71&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/949835e2077b5e45aab26aadc2967c71/'&gt;Equal Height Columns&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also consider letting the height be driven by the content. The W3C specs are basically written to support content-driven boxes. Letting the content drive the height will save you many headaches down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can set a height that fits your content. The most important thing is being intentional with height. Knowing how setting a height will affect your site is powerful knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Position&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Document flow is tied with the box model for the CSS concepts I think are most important. Tuts+ has a great article on normal document flow, &lt;a href=&quot;http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/articles/quick-tip-utilizing-normal-document-flow--webdesign-8199&quot;&gt;Quick Tip: Utilizing Normal Document Flow&lt;/a&gt;. In the article they describe normal document flow as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
[H]ow a page is presented when you do nothing to it with regard to structural styling.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://info.cern.ch/hypertext/WWW/TheProject.html&quot;&gt;first web page&lt;/a&gt; is a great example of normal document flow. You can see that nothing sits on the same line as the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; of the page. The default display value for a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;block&lt;/code&gt;. The inverse is true for the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags that appear within the first paragraph. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tags have a default display value of &lt;code&gt;inline&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confusion can occur when things are both in the normal document flow and outside of it. Not understanding this property may result in undesirable results. For example, you will be disappointed if you add an absolutely positioned logo at the top of the page and expect your navigation to sit next to the logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;234&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;30cff6e84d84ee78728ad4509720fe37&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/30cff6e84d84ee78728ad4509720fe37/'&gt;30cff6e84d84ee78728ad4509720fe37&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops, why are things sitting on top of each other? Well, elements in the normal document flow are ignoring the heart logo since it was taken out of the normal document flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/guilh&quot;&gt;Guil  Hernandez&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; course on &lt;a href=&quot;teamtreehouse.com&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamtreehouse.com/library/css-layout-techniques&quot;&gt;CSS Layout Techniques&lt;/a&gt; is one of the best explanations for layout complexities that I have come across. Treehouse costs a few bucks a month, but it worth the price of admission. Consider taking his course if you find stuff isn&amp;#39;t laying out like you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Center Alignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Center alignment was one of those things that I had to look up every time for a long time. Not even vertical alignment, which can be solved &lt;a href=&quot;http://zerosixthree.se/vertical-align-anything-with-just-3-lines-of-css/&quot;&gt;in three lines&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://philipwalton.github.io/solved-by-flexbox/demos/vertical-centering/&quot;&gt;by flexbox&lt;/a&gt;. There are a bunch of techniques for centering. Each is used for different situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four basic ways to horizontally center items:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For block-level containers &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/almanac/properties/t/text-align/&quot;&gt;text-align: center;&lt;/a&gt; will center that container&amp;#39;s inline or inline-block elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For absolutely positioned elements with a known or unknown width &lt;a href=&quot;https://teamtreehouse.com/forum/centre-align-an-absolute-positioned-element-with-unknown-width&quot;&gt;left: 0; right: 0; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&lt;/a&gt; will center that element&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For block-level elements with a width margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; will center that element and its content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For parent elements that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/snippets/css/a-guide-to-flexbox/&quot;&gt;display: flex;&lt;/a&gt;, justify-content: center; will center all child elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is everything in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;156&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;3b11a5a3f76e7b2c461fc72406647957&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/3b11a5a3f76e7b2c461fc72406647957/'&gt;3b11a5a3f76e7b2c461fc72406647957&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on centering, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/centering-css-complete-guide/_&quot;&gt;Centering in CSS: A Complete Guide&lt;/a&gt; on CSS-Tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the most simple display tasks can be difficult in CSS. Don&amp;#39;t worry if you have to look up how to do something once or twenty times. Everyone is learning together. Visit the sites I link to throughout this article if you&amp;#39;re having any of these problems. Or contact me on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenJoyceCT&quot;&gt;@BenJoyceCT&lt;/a&gt; and I can try to help. Let me know if you notice any issues with the article. Best of luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/front-end%20development/2015/07/25/css-mistkaes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/front-end%20development/2015/07/25/css-mistkaes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Design Decisions Quote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I think we&amp;#39;re at our best when we&amp;#39;re at our weirdest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//quote/2015/07/24/weirdest-quote.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//quote/2015/07/24/weirdest-quote.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Quote</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tools I Use: Pocket</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve tried all sorts of tools to help me save and organize links. Recently, I started using &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;. The app has been around since 2007 (previously known as Read it Later). I&amp;#39;m happy to be a late adopter as it is now integrated into all the applications I could possibly imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;ve ever wanted to save a link from &lt;a href=&quot;http://help.getpocket.com/customer/portal/articles/482762-how-to-save-from-twitter-for-iphone&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/chrome/&quot;&gt;Chrome&lt;/a&gt;, or any of the other &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpocket.com/apps/&quot;&gt;500 supported apps&lt;/a&gt;, give Pocket a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/2015/07/15/tools-i-use.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/2015/07/15/tools-i-use.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How I Built It: Fourth of July</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first of my planned &amp;quot;walk through&amp;quot; posts. Today I&amp;#39;m writing about the process I went through to create the pen I made for the Fourth of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a few key points during this exercise. You can skip ahead to one of them if you&amp;#39;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#design&quot;&gt;Picking colors and a design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fill&quot;&gt;SVG fill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#loop&quot;&gt;Sass loops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#shadow&quot;&gt;filter: drop-shadow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, here is the final:
&lt;p data-height=&quot;809&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;16322&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;gpvzNK&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;benjoyce&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce/pen/gpvzNK/'&gt;Fourth of July&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Joyce (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/benjoyce'&gt;@benjoyce&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, cool. Go America! Let&amp;#39;s learn something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Picking colors and a design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspiration for this pen came from a question asked at trivia last week. The final question asked us to list 11 of the 13 original US colonies. We were able to do it, but I struggled more than I thought I would. So I decided my next SVG exercise would also be a history lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by finding a &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Blank_US_Map.svg&quot;&gt;US map&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Commons&lt;/a&gt; has a ton of SVG files. Although they are a good starting point, most of them are not optimized. This particular file is massive. 79kb for one SVG probably means that there are a ton of points. The computer has to calculate and display each point. More calculations means more tax on your processor. Going to production with a file this large may result in a negative experience for your users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/video-screencasts/137-svg-is-for-everybody/&quot;&gt;SVG is for everybody&lt;/a&gt;, but be careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had the map I had to figure out what I wanted to do with it. I dropped it in CodePen and started messing around. For these types of fun exercises I often go to  &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt; and look for inspiration. I typed &amp;quot;USA&amp;quot; into the search bar on Dribbble and started flipping through examples. I lifted the red in my example from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/zgraham&quot;&gt;Zach Grahm&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; shot, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/shots/973557-That-One-Place&quot;&gt;That One Place&lt;/a&gt;. I tried filling the background with red, but that looked pretty junky with the map on top. I held onto the red until I knew exactly what I was doing with the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;#39;t find anything on the web that gave me inspiration for how to fill the states. I decided that the stars from the flag would look cool. I created a small SVG file containing a star on a blue background. I played with the colors I had chosen in Illustrator to make sure that they would work well together. From there I had to figure out how to get the stars into the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fill&quot;&gt;SVG Fill&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have used an SVG then you have used the &lt;code&gt;fill&lt;/code&gt; property. &lt;code&gt;Fill&lt;/code&gt; determines what happens inside of the thing that is defined by points. Right or wrong, I think of &lt;code&gt;fill&lt;/code&gt; in the same way I think of &lt;code&gt;background&lt;/code&gt; in CSS. If you&amp;#39;re just working with a color, then &lt;code&gt;fill&lt;/code&gt; is pretty similar to &lt;code&gt;background&lt;/code&gt;. However, things get a little different once you start introducing images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to know is that the definition of your image source must happen in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;defs&lt;/code&gt; are inserted right after the opening &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;svg&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag. Here is how my &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;defs&lt;/code&gt; looks:
&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;defs&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;pattern height=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; id=&amp;quot;img1&amp;quot; patternUnits=&amp;quot;userSpaceOnUse&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
      &amp;lt;image height=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; width=&amp;quot;150&amp;quot; x=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; xlink:href=&amp;quot;https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/s.cdpn.io/97391/star.svg&amp;quot; y=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/pattern&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;/defs&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four key pieces of the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pattern&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; definition to focus on. The first is the pattern &lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;/code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt;. You can think of these definitions as the size of the container that the image sits in. If you set the size of the pattern to anything larger than the size of the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;image&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; there will be extra space around the image. I wanted the stars to be tight against each other. To make sure there was no extra space I set the &lt;code&gt;height&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;width&lt;/code&gt; of the pattern and the image to the exact same value. You&amp;#39;ll notice that these values do not have any unit definitions. Unit-less size definitions default to pixels throughout different parts of SVG markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; must be defined for the pattern. The &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; is used later to reference the pattern from the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;pattern&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; definition. I happened to use CSS to set the fill of the states. You will be able to reference the &lt;code&gt;id&lt;/code&gt; from the CSS and the browser will know what to do with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
.state {
  fill: url(#img1);
  fill-opacity: 0;
  stroke:#f5f5f5;
  stroke-width:1;
  stroke-opacity:1;
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a good time to mention an interesting feature about using patterns for fills in SVG. The pattern will repeat itself how you would expect. In my SVG file there are multiple states. Each state has a separate &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;path&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; definition. Still, the single image defined in the pattern repeats itself across the patterns to form one, cohesive pattern. I don&amp;#39;t know the technical details on how it works, but it does and it&amp;#39;s cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final thing I thought about in the definition is the &lt;code&gt;xlink:href&lt;/code&gt;. The source can be any image file type that you would expect (.svg, .jpg, .png, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for reference, I dug into info on &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/SVG/Tutorial/Patterns&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt; and a question someone answered on &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3796025/fill-svg-path-element-with-a-background-image&quot;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;loop&quot;&gt;Sass Loops&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thesassway.com/intermediate/if-for-each-while&quot;&gt;Control directives&lt;/a&gt; are one of my favorite reasons for using Sass. I have found &lt;code&gt;for&lt;/code&gt; loops to be particularly useful. In this example I wanted to add a short time delay between each state increasing its &lt;code&gt;fill-opacity&lt;/code&gt;. There are a few ways to get this result. You could add a different class to each state and set the &lt;code&gt;animation-delay&lt;/code&gt; to a slightly different value for each. That would be messy and take too much time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The better option is to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/the-difference-between-nth-child-and-nth-of-type/&quot;&gt;nth-of-type&lt;/a&gt; combined with a &lt;code&gt;for&lt;/code&gt; loop. The loop I set up goes through each element with the class &lt;code&gt;state&lt;/code&gt;. During the loop &lt;code&gt;$i&lt;/code&gt; gets updated by 1. We can use the variable in multiple places. I use the same variable that gets updated during the loop to change the number in the &lt;code&gt;nth-of-type&lt;/code&gt; psuedo class. I also use the variable in the &lt;code&gt;animation-delay&lt;/code&gt; equation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
@for $i from 1 through $states {
  .state:nth-of-type(#{$i}){
    animation: flash 1s linear 1 forwards;
    animation-delay: ($i*0.15)+s;
  }
}
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think finding good ways to use control directives is the main benefit of these creative exercises. They allow you to think analytically and build good foundations for programming in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shadow&quot;&gt;Filter: drop-shadow&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never used the &lt;code&gt;drop-shadow&lt;/code&gt; property before this exercise. It&amp;#39;s an awesome way to do what you hoped &lt;code&gt;box-shadow&lt;/code&gt; would do on your SVG. The difference is &lt;code&gt;drop-shadow&lt;/code&gt; calculates the area of the element it is being applied to and acts accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#39;ll notice that in the example the shadow fits nicely around each state. Unfortunately that calculation comes at a processing cost. When I had the &lt;code&gt;drop-shadow&lt;/code&gt; being applied immediately to each state it basically crashed the browser. That is because the browser was calculating where to put the points in the SVG, calculating the points that the drop shadow needed to go around, and running an animation. Even on my high-end device there were problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To fix the problem I added an animation to the drop shadow that was delayed by the time it took to fill each state plus a few milliseconds. The whole example is still expensive, but the delay helped quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone ever wanted a similar graphic on their site there are a few things to think about. The first, and most important, is the size of the SVG. The map does not need to be nearly as precise as the one I used. Think about using your design chops to find a solution that is smaller but conveys the same message. The other thing to remember is that some of this stuff is experimental. For example, &lt;code&gt;filter&lt;/code&gt; seems to be forever messed up in IE. Always check &lt;a href=&quot;caniuse.com&quot;&gt;Can I Use&lt;/a&gt; before using any experimental properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you need help with anything I mentioned above. Also, please let me know if you think something is inaccurate and I&amp;#39;ll fix it. The best way to reach me is on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BenJoyceCT&quot;&gt;@BenJoyceCT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//article/design/front-end%20development/2015/07/05/how-i-built-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//article/design/front-end%20development/2015/07/05/how-i-built-it.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Article</category>
        
        <category>Design</category>
        
        <category>Front-End Development</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
