<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Benjamin Joyce&#39;s blog</title>
    <description>Posts about the web, business, and other stuff I do in my free time.</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 23:12:41 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 23:12:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything is Gone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pro-tip: Be super careful when using Git for the first time. Just felt the classic pain of deleting about 3 hours of work on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patient person in me says it&amp;#39;s a learning experience. The patient person better get the hell out of this room.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com//2015/06/22/everything-is-gone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com//2015/06/22/everything-is-gone.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello, benjaminjoyce.com</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 2015. It&amp;#39;s getting late and I have work tomorrow. Yet, I&amp;#39;m taking this time to launch a blog. Mine won&amp;#39;t be much different than the millions of others already on the internet. Yet, it&amp;#39;s a special moment for me. It&amp;#39;s not the first time I have launched a personal website. I first launched something back in 2010. That site, it&amp;#39;s content, and snapshot of that time is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those forgotten memories is why I write again today. I don&amp;#39;t want to forget. I want to look back at how bad of a writer I am. I want to see when I learned what I learned. This blog will have everything from CSS tips to personal achievements and failures. I am taking an oath not to delete my posts due to embarrassment, pressure, or other forces. Benjaminjoyce.com is a reflection of me, at the time of each post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s all I have for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com//2015/06/21/hello-benjaminjoycedotcom.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com//2015/06/21/hello-benjaminjoycedotcom.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
